

# ANUP KUMAR SARKAR

**Software Engineer** 



+8801676667712

github.com/MeAnupSarkar

in linkedin.com/in/iamanup

Mirpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh

# **Work Experience**

#### **Healthcare Pharmaceuticals Ltd**

Software Engineer, Executive

01/12/2020 - Present

Developed & published complete sales & marketing automations software solutions for Pharmaceuticals Industry.

- Successfully connected internal & external sales, marketing as well as other management team & departments with external partner via newly developed automated system.
- Newly developed system leads to 50% more efficient workflow & effective data tracking & sharing by removing bottlenecks.
- Analyzed & architected business intelligence models to measure ROI, KPI, Risk & Asset management.
- Introduced new cutting-edge modern technologies by removing legacy system.

#### The Dhaka Mercantile Co-operative Bank Ltd.

Software Engineer, AEO

01/01/2018 - 01/11/2020

Build up from scratch an Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) solution software for Banking Sector & published to the cloud.

- Implementing comprehensive ERP software not only provides access to important data, also enabling a better process for collecting and analyzing data
- Better processes and communication lead to increased efficiency and enhanced company performance Moving data from the old legacy system and mapping it into the new ERP.
- Successfully developed Interconnected Realtime system using cutting edge modern technologies

#### Education

#### **Bachelor of Computer Applications**

2014-2017

Lovely Professional University, Punjab, India **CGPA:** 7.7 out of 10

#### **Extra Curriculum Activities:**

- 1. Participated Project Expo-2017(Project Displayed: ExoVisix)
- 2. Participated Explorica-2016 (Project Displayed: StudyPhobia)
- 3. Participated in Hacker Rank World cup Competition

# Certifications

Microsoft Asp.Net MVC Core with SQL Server 2017

BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM)

Duration: 09/2020 - 10/2020

# Career Summary

Over 3.5 years of demonstrated experience in designing, architecting and supporting enterpriselevel internet scale services/solutions hosted on Cloud and On-premise technologies. Experience working closely with Software Engineering, especially in the aspects of system performance, capacity management and scalability to ensure sustained service stability & Business KPI's.



# Skills & Expertise

### **Software Development Life Cycle**

Creating vision, Ideation & design thinking, estimates & planning, develop, test, deploy, maintenance, project management & innovation using technologies.

#### **Specialization**

Full Stack Web Development **Android Application Development** 

#### **Architectures and Principles**

SPA, SOLID, MVC, MVVM, MVP, Micro front-ends

#### **Programming languages**

C# (.Net), JAVA, Typescript, Php, C/C++

#### Web Technologies

ASP.Net Core/MVC, EF/EF Core, React, Redux, Webpack, ¡Query, Codelgniter, Syncfusion, ¡Query DataTable, HTML5, CSS3

#### **Data Management**

MS SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite, Azure SQL DB, SSIS, SSRS, SSDT, Crystal Report, RDLC Report

Azure (App Services, VM, SQL Database), CI/CD: GitHub Actions, Azure DevOps

### **Machine Learning**

Computer Vision using OpenCV & JAVACV

## Framework & Library

Android Room, Retrofit, JavaFX, OpenCV, LINQ, Entity Framework, Automapper, Select2

#### Other

Parallel Processing & Concurrency in C#, Generic, Reflections, Dependency Injection



# **S** WEB APPLICATIONS

#### 1. DMCBL ERP

A complete ERP solution having HRM, CRM, PF, Loan, Banking & Centralized Attendance for The Dhaka Mercantile Co Operative Bank Ltd **Tech Stack:** Asp.net MVC 5, Entity Framework, MS SQL Server 2017, Razor Pages, Bootstrap, jQuery, Crystal Reports, jQuery Datatables

#### 2. Sales & Marketing Activities for Pharmaceuticals Industry

Project containing various sales & marketing automations module creating efficient workflow & effective data tracking & sharing by removing bottlenecks. **Tech Stack:** Dotnet Core 5.0, EF Core, MS SQL Server 2017, Syncfusion, RDLC

Reporting , Bootstrap , jQuery **Link:** https://ddf.hplbd.com/

#### 3. XEOVENTORY POS & Accounting

Complete solution for POS, Sales, Purchases, Productions, Customers, Suppliers, Transactions, Ledgers, Journal, Receipts & Payments with various reports.

**Tech Stack:** Asp.net MVC 5, Entity Framework, MS SQL Server **Link:** https://xeoventory.azurewebsites.net

#### 4. SapientCerts - Sapient Universal Certifications

Providing real time certificate audit & verifications using QR Code & other technologies.

**Tech Stack:** ASP.NET Core 5.0 WebAPI, EF Core 5.0, ASP.NET Core Identity, AJAX for CRUD, Clean Architecture

Link: http://sapientcert.com/

#### 5. HelloHi Parking

Book/reserve parking spot for your Vehicle anywhere in different cities in US. **Tech Stack**: Php, Codelgniter, MySQL, Bootstrap, Paypal Payment Gateway Link: <a href="https://hellohiparking.com/">https://hellohiparking.com/</a>

# Open Source Contributions (Desktop Apps)

#### 1. ExoVisix: (AI & Computer Vision)

Auto Attendance System Using Real Time Face Recognition with Various Computer Vision & Machine Learning Tools.

Attendance system Using Face Recognition, Face Trainer, Motion Detection OCR, Gesture Control, Rectangle Shape Detection, Eye Detection.

**Tech Stack:** Core Java, JavaCV (wrapper of Opency), JavaFX, MySQL, Maven, Tesseract OCR Framework

GitHub Link: https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/ExoVisix

YouTube Demo: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6UnBZFvY8HE&t=533s

#### 2. XEOCORP Bulk Card Generator:

Generate Bulk/Multiple Business Card by reading files from folder

Tech Stack: Java, JavaFx, Google zxing

Link: <a href="https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/Xeocorp-Card-Generator-JavaFX">https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/Xeocorp-Card-Generator-JavaFX</a>
YouTube Demo: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VVIrRC3KttA&t=48s">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VVIrRC3KttA&t=48s</a>

#### 3. React Redux Typescript Webpack Boilerplate:

Frontend Boilerplate with React, Redux, TypeScript, Webpack, Babel, Ant Design & many more

Link: https://github.com/MeAnupSarkar/ReactReduxTsTemplate

# **ANDROID APPLICATIONS**

#### 1. Vara123

Book or Rent the perfect Accommodation, Parking Spots, Vehicle Rentals in anytime, anywhere in Bangladesh.

Playstore: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.brosoft.vara123

#### 2. BCAS

Android app for content & book sharing for The Institute of Cost and Management Accountants of Bangladesh (ICMAB)

#### 3. HelloHi Parking

Book/reserve parking spot using android app.

Playstore: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.brosoft.hellohiparking

# ★ Languages

Bengali - Native (Read/Write/Speak)
 English - Fluent (Read/Write/Speak)

3. Hindi - Good (Speaking)

# Hobbies & Interests

1. Robotics & Al, Devops, IoT, Blockchain, Automation

2. Cosmology, Science, Travelling

3. History, Ancient Civilizations

4. Sports: Cricket, Chess, Football, Pool

### Educational Details

#### **Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA)**

Lovely Professional University, Punjab, India 2014-2017

CGPA: 7.7 out of 10

### **Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)**

FM International College, Dhaka 2009-2011

GPA: 4.70 out of 5.0

#### **Secondary School Certificate (SSC)**

Mirpur Siddhanta High School, Dhaka

2007-2009

GPA: 4.69 out of 5.0

# Personal Information

Father's Name : Kartik Chandra Sarkar

Mother's Name : Anta Rani Sarkar

**Permanent Address** : 110/B, Coatbari, Darus

Salam, Mirpur-1, Dhaka

Date of Birth : 13th July 1993

Nationality : Bangladeshi

Gender : Male

National ID : 19932694809000112

Marital Status : Unmarried

#### Declarations

I, the undersigned do hereby state that to the base of my knowledge and belief, the above-mentioned data correctly described my qualification.

(Signature)